Danyang Zhuo

Assistant Professor Department of Computer Science Trinity College of Arts and Sciences Duke University August 16, 2020 308 Research Dr Durham, NC 27705 danyang@cs.duke.edu https://danyangzhuo.com

Research Interests

I do research broadly in computer systems, including operating systems, distributed systems, and computer networks, with a focus on the design and implementation of data center systems to support today's increasingly data-intensive applications. My current research includes cloud operating systems that support efficient and flexible containerization, high-performance distributed data-processing systems, and correct and efficient middleboxes and network function virtualization.

Education

University of Washington – Seattle

Seattle, Washington

Ph.D. in Computer Science and Engineering

Sep 2013 - Aug 2019

- Dissertation: Practical, Efficient, and Reliable Data Center Communication.
- Advisors: Thomas E. Anderson, Arvind Krishnamurthy

University of Illinois – Urbana Champaign

B.S. in Electrical Engineering

Advisor: Nitin Vaidya

Urbana, Illinois Aug 2009 - May 2013

Professional Experience

•	Duke University Assistant Professor of Computer Science	Durham, North Carolina Jul 2020 - now
•	University of California – Berkeley Postdoctoral Researcher – Advisor: Ion Stoica	Berkeley, California Sep 2019 - Jun 2020
•	Microsoft Research Contractor (through Populous Group)	Redmond, Washington Oct 2015 - Feb 2017
•	Microsoft Research Research Intern	Redmond, Washington Jun 2015 - Sep 2015
•	Google Software Development Engineering Intern	Mountain View, California Sep 2014 - Mar 2015
•	Amazon Software Development Engineering Intern	Seattle, Washington May 2013 - Sep 2013
•	Microsoft Software Development Engineering Intern	Redmond, Washington May 2012 - Aug 2012

Publications

Conference Papers

- 1. Lianmin Zheng, Chengfan Jia, Minmin Sun, Zhao Wu, Cody Hao Yu, Ameer Haj-Ali, Yida Wang, Jun Yang, **Danyang Zhuo**, Koushik Sen, Joseph E. Gonzalez, Ion Stoica. *Ansor: Generating High-Performance Tensor Programs for Deep Learning*. The 14th USENIX Symposium on Operating Systems Design and Implementation (OSDI), 2020.
- 2. Kaiyuan Zhang, **Danyang Zhuo**, Arvind Krishnamurthy. *Gallium: Automated Software Middlebox Offloading to Programmable Switches*. In Proceedings of the Conference of the ACM Special Interest Group on Data Communication (SIGCOMM), 2020.
- 3. Kaiyuan Zhang, **Danyang Zhuo**, Aditya Akella, Arvind Krishnamurthy, Xi Wang. *Automated Verification of Customizable Middlebox Properties with Gravel*. The 17th USENIX Symposium on Networked Systems Design and Implementation (NSDI), 2020.
- 4. **Danyang Zhuo**, Kaiyuan Zhang, Yibo Zhu, Hongqiang Harry Liu, Matthew Rockett, Arvind Krishnamurthy, Thomas Anderson. *Slim: OS Kernel Support for a Low-Overhead Container Overlay Network*. The 16th USENIX Symposium on Networked Systems Design and Implementation (NSDI), 2019.
- Danyang Zhuo, Monia Ghobadi, Ratul Mahajan, Klaus-Tycho Förster, Arvind Krishnamurthy and Thomas E. Anderson. *Understanding and Mitigating Packet Corruption in Data Center* Networks. In Proceedings of the Conference of the ACM Special Interest Group on Data Communication (SIGCOMM), 2017.
- Danyang Zhuo, Monia Ghobadi, Ratul Mahajan, Amar Phanishayee, Xuan Kelvin Zou, Hang Guan, Arvind Krishnamurthy and Thomas E. Anderson. RAIL: A Case for Redundant Arrays of Inexpensive Links in Data Center Networks. The 14th USENIX Symposium on Networked Systems Design and Implementation (NSDI), 2017.
- 7. Vincent Liu, **Danyang Zhuo**, Simon Peter, Arvind Krishnamurthy and Thomas E. Anderson. Subways: A Case for Redundant, Inexpensive Data Center Edge Links. The 13th International Conference on emerging Networking EXperiments and Technologies (CoNEXT), 2015.

Workshop Papers

- Samantha Miller, Kaiyuan Zhang, Danyang Zhuo, Shibin Xu, Arvind Krishnamurthy, Thomas Anderson. Practical Safe Linux Kernel Extensibility. The 17th Workshop on Hot Topics in Operating Systems (HotOS), 2019.
- Danyang Zhuo, Qiao Zhang, Xin Yang, Vincent Liu. Canaries in the Network. The 15th ACM Workshop on Hot Topics in Networks (HotNets), 2016.
- 3. **Danyang Zhuo**, Qiao Zhang, Vincent Liu, Arvind Krishnamurthy, Thomas E. Anderson. *Rack-level Congestion Control.* The 15th ACM Workshop on Hot Topics in Networks (HotNets), 2016.
- Danyang Zhuo, Qiao Zhang, Dan Ports, Arvind Krishnamurthy, Thomas E. Anderson. Machine Fault Tolerance for Reliable Datacenter Systems. The 5th Asia-Pacific Workshop on Systems (APSys), 2014.

Patents

1. Monia Ghobadi, Ratul Mahajan, Amar Phanishayee, **Danyang Zhuo**, Xuan Kelvin Zou. *Data Center Topology Having Multiple Classes of Reliability*. US Patent 20170302565A1. WIPO Patent 2017180450A1.

Awards			
University of Washington Madrona Prize Runner-Up			
Invited Talk			
• Towards Efficient and Reliable Data Center Systems.			
 Yale University Purdue University University of Virginia Duke University Rutgers University Microsoft Research Penn State University University of Minnesota Slim: OS Kernel Support for a Low-Overhead Container Overlay Network. 	Apr 2019 Apr 2019 Mar 2019 Mar 2019 Mar 2019 Feb 2019 Feb 2019		
- Princeton University	Jun 2020 Feb 2019		
• Understanding and Mitigating Packet Corruption in Data Center Networks.			
- ACM SIGCOMM • RAIL: A Case for Redundant Arrays of Inexpensive Links in Data Center New - USENIX NSDI	Aug 2017 tworks. Mar 2017		

Teaching

• CPS 510: Advanced Operating Systems. (Fall 2020)

Service

Program Committee

• SIGCOMM (2020)